卡塞尔
Castle.
别过去  你帮不了他
Stay back! There's nothing you can do!
天啊
Oh, my god!
卡塞尔
Castle.
是空的
It's empty.
他不在
He's not here.
他不在车里
He's not in the car!
你确定
You sure he's not in the car?
即使烧到那个温度  也会留下遗骸
Even with a fire that hot, there'd still be a body.
他肯定在附近
He's got to be nearby.
-你真觉得...  -他还活着  肯定的
- You really think he... - He's here. He has to be.
-我们得赶快找  -我们需要人手
- We have to start a search. - We could use more men.
警佐
Sergeant!
我是贝克特探长  纽约警局
I'm detective Beckett, NYPD.
那辆车的驾驶员是我们自己人
The man that was in that car is one of our own.
-我们要彻底搜索这一带  -我立刻派人去
- We need to scrub every inch of this area. - I'll get my men on it.
你们有搜救狗吗
You have search-and-rescue dogs?
-我去叫支援  -好
- I'll call them in. - Okay.
我得去帮忙
I need to help them.
你穿成这样帮不上忙
You're no use to anyone dressed like that.
我们马上开始  你去换衣服
We'll get started here. You go change.
走吧  我们给你换件衣服
Come on. Let's get you into some other clothes.
好的  我就回来
Okay, I'll be right back.
好了  我沿着路边找
All right. I'm gonna search up near the road.
或许卡塞尔在撞车之前跳车了
Maybe Castle managed to bail out before the car crashed.
我去看看车
All right, we'll start on the car,
-看看能不能查明情况  或是他的去向  -好
- see if we can tell - what happened or where he went. - All right.
气囊冲气了
Airbag went off.
只有座位上有人才会启动
It only activates - when someone's in that seat,
这么说他当时的确在车上
So your man - was definitely at the wheel.
但他跑出来了
Yeah, but if he walked away,
他人呢  而且为什么不接电话
where is he, - and why isn't he picking up?
或许手机摔坏了
Maybe his phone's damaged
或者撞迷糊了
or he's disoriented.
这情况我见识过
I've seen it before.
如果他下了车
But if he left this vehicle,
应该能查到足迹或血迹
there's gonna be tracks or a blood trail.
-喂  -哈维
- Hello. - Hey, Javi.
去看看卡塞尔车的后面
Walk to the back of Castle's car.
-干吗  -照做就是了
- What for? - Just do it, okay?
看看副驾后侧
Check the passenger rear side.
告诉我什么情况
Tell me what you see.
看来右侧被撞过
Looks like it took a hit on the right side,
尾灯撞坏了
Busted a taillight.
因为卡塞尔是被别的车撞了
That's 'cause Castle got bumped by another car
才冲下道路
and run off the road.
我在碎片这里
I got debris up here.
好  叫鉴证组来
All right, call local CSU.
或许能通过碎片知道是什么车
Maybe those pieces - can help us I.D. that car.
警探  我有发现
Detective, I think I got something.
足迹
Tracks.
从车上下来  往那边走了
Going from the car up to the road.
水冲掉了一些痕迹  但看来有三个人
Water washed part of the trail, but it looks like three people.
三个人  不会啊
Three people? That can't be right.
看到土里的两道痕迹了吗
See the two troughs in the dirt?
是一双鞋的鞋跟留下的
Made by heels from a pair of shoes.
那么说他被赶下了路  然后又被从车上拖了下来
So he was run off the road then dragged from the car.
卡塞尔被人抓走了
Castle got grabbed.
-什么情况  -我让泰吉特设了路障
- What? - I had Taggert set up roadblocks
拦截搜查每一辆车
to stop and search every vehicle.
我们认为卡塞尔可能就在
We figured that the car that ran Castle into the ditch
把他撞下路的那辆车上
may be the same car he's in now.
-知道什么车了吗  -不知道  但鉴证组认为
- Okay, we get a description? - Not yet, but CSU thinks
那些碎片是一辆通用上面掉下来的
the side-marker glass up ahead came from a GM.
当地警方在进行排查
Local P.D. is canvassing
询问是否有人看到车辆离开这一带
to see if anyone saw any vehicles leaving the area.
-卡塞尔的手机呢  -营运商说他关机了
- What about Castle's cellphone? - His provider says it's shut off.
我们联系了联调局看看能不能远程启动
Contacted the FBI to see if it could be turned on remotely.
希望不大  但也未必
It's a long shot, but you never know.
-还有什么  -凯特
- What else? - Kate...
我们已经尽了一切全力
Everything that can be done is being done.
埃斯波  别说这种话
Espo, don't tell me that.
他们绑走了他  我必须做点什么
They took him. I need to do something.
那跟我们说说你接到的那通电话
Then tell us about that phone call you got.
他当时紧张吗
Was he nervous?
他有暗示说他被跟踪了吗
Did he indicate in any way he was being followed?
没有  他...
No, he was just...
很正常  一切都很正常
...Normal. He was normal.
泰吉特警佐可能找到了目击者
Hey, sergeant Taggert may have a witness.
在前面摆水果摊
Guy runs a fruit stand up the road.
是的  我在你们说的时间段
Yeah, I definitely saw a mercedes go by
看到一辆梅赛德斯驶过  青铜色
around the time you're talking... bronze-colored.
那是卡塞尔的车
That's Castle's car.
-那之后有其他的车吗  -我想想
- What about any cars after that? - Uh, let's see.
一辆大众甲壳虫  一辆法拉利  一辆SUV
There was a volkswagen bug, a Ferrari, an SUV.
不会有人开甲壳虫或者法拉利把他逼下路
No one's gonna run him off the road with a bug or a Ferrari.
跟我说说那辆SUV的情况
Talk to me about that SUV.
是一辆凯雷德
It was an Escalade --
黑色车  有色车窗和铬合金车轮
Black with tinted windows and chrome wheels.
你怎么碰巧记得这么清楚
How is it you happen to remember it so clearly?
因为我看见了两次
Because I saw it twice.
他往北开  路过一次
He passed heading north.
大约十分钟后  又飞驰而过
Then he blew by again maybe 10 minutes later.
他们拉着卡塞尔离开长岛一路朝南
They were headed south off of Long Island with Castle.
我去对那辆凯雷德发布全境通告
I'll put out an APB on the Escalade.
我去给州警察打电话  让他们
I'm gonna call state police, have them set up checkpoints
在离开长岛的每一条路上设立检查站
at every road leading off of Long Island.
他们可能不是打算带卡塞尔离开长岛
Getting Castle off the island may not be the plan.
联调局刚打来了电话
The feds just called.
他们成功地远程激活了卡塞尔的电话
They were able to remotely activate Castle's phone
大概持续了几秒钟
for a few seconds.
他们查到位置了吗
Did they get a location?
是啊  他还在岛上
Yeah, he's still on the island.
根据他的卫星定位  十分钟前
According to his GPS, as of 10 minutes ago,
他在德福德
he was in Medford.
德福德离这里有多远
How far is Medford from here?
我一路疾驰过去  不会很远的
Not far the way I'm gonna drive.
卡塞尔的卫星定位
It says Castle's GPS
显示他在废车场往里一百英尺的地方
puts him at a hundred feet into this junkyard.
州警察十分钟后就到了
State police are 10 minutes out.
他们想让你们等待支援
They want you to wait for backup.
绝不可能
Not a chance in hell.
就在那边
It's right over there.
85英尺  正在靠近
85 feet and closing.
哪边
Which way?
我想是这辆汽车运输车的另一边
Other side of this car carrier, I think.
现在距离60英尺
60 feet now.
那里
There.
黑色的凯雷德
Black Escalade.
是啊
Yeah.
那是卡塞尔卫星定位的位置
That's ground zero for Castle's GPS.
所以他在车里
So he's in there.
不
No.
站住
Stop!
不要动
Do not move!
站住
Stop!
-趴下  不许动  -站住
- On the ground! Don't move! - Freeze!
马上趴下
On the ground now!
你做了什么
What have you done?!
-你做了什么  -贝克特  我们抓到他了
- What have you done?! - Beckett! We got him! We got him!
-不  -贝克特  住手
- No! - Beckett, stop!
不  不
No! No!
加里·达芬
Gary Duffin.
你对审讯室很熟悉
You're no stranger to rooms like this.
但这次不一样了
But this time it's different.
这次你唯一的选择就是给我答案
This time, your only option is to give me answers.
如果我不给呢
And what if I don't?
那辆SUV开进去时  你在废车场
You were in the junkyard when that SUV came in.
谁在车里
Who was in it?
知道吗
You know what?
我要律师
I want a lawyer.
你是个低等的人渣  加里
You're a low-level dirtbag, Gary.
你可不是犯罪首脑  所以快点交代
You're not a criminal mastermind, so start talking.
车里有谁
Who was in the car?
是谁让你粉碎汽车的
Who had you crush it?
卡塞尔在车里吗
Was Castle in the car?
他在车里吗
Was he in the car?
他还活着吗
Was he alive?
你要折断我的手指了
Aah! You're gonna break my finger!
折断一根还有九根
And then after that, there's nine more,
快告诉我我想知道的
so tell me what I want to know.
快交代的
Start talking.
我没什么好说的
I got nothing to say.
怎么了
What? What is it?
法医对SUV的检查结果出来了
Forensics came back on the SUV.
没有血液或者组织
There was no blood or tissue.
卡塞尔不在车里
Castle wasn't inside.
好吧
Okay.
那他还活着
So he's still out there.
这就说明他们粉碎那辆车来掩盖行踪
Which means they crushed the car to cover their tracks.
让鉴证组寻找DNA和指纹
Okay, get CSU to sweep for dna and prints.
把加里·达芬送去拘留室
And let's move Gary Duffin to a holding cell.
好让你对他干什么
So you can do what to him?
我之前在看
I was watching.
动粗是无济于事的
Getting booted off the force is not gonna help anything.
埃斯波  他知道是谁绑架了卡塞尔
Espo, he knows who took Castle.
他不会供出那些人的
Well, he's never gonna give them up.
不管那些人是谁  比起你来
Whoever they are, he's way more afraid of them
他更害怕他们
than he is of you.
好吧  我们会采取另一种方式
Fine. We'll try another angle...
暂时如此
For now.
谢谢
Thanks.
SUV这条线索断了
So, we are dead-ended on the SUV.
查了车牌号
Ran the vin number.
原来这辆车是从
Turns out that it was stolen
肯尼迪机场附近的一处长期停车场被盗的
from a long-term parking lot near JFK
而那里的视频监控很糟糕
with conveniently lousy video surveillance.
好吧  再深入查查碎车的这个加里·达芬
okay, let's dig deeper into our car-crusher, Gary Duffin...
查查他的背景  他的联系人
Look into his background, his known associates.
也许能让我们找到绑架卡塞尔的人
That might lead us to whoever took Castle.
马上去
We're on it.
警探  能聊聊吗
Detective. Do you have a moment?
好的  长官
Yes, sir.
你还好吗
How are you holding up?
我没事
I'm fine.
我无法想象你的感受
I truly can't imagine what you're going through,
这种时候你怎么能集中精力
how you can focus at a time like this.
长官  请别把我撤出这案子
Uh, sir, please don't take me off of this case.
我不会  除非你让我非这么做不可
Oh, I won't...unless you give me cause to.
你继续做你的事
You keep doing what you're doing.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
另外  希望你知道
And you should know we're using
我们正在动用一切资源去寻找卡塞尔先生
every resource that we have to find Mr. Castle,
包括向联调局求助
including calling in the FBI.
有位叫康纳的特别探员在等你
There's a special agent Connors waiting to speak with you.
长官  恕我直言  我现在压力很大
Sir, with all due respect, I-I'm under the gun here.
没时间协助联调局了解情况
I don't have time to bring the FBI up to speed.
情况我已经了解了  探长
I'm already up to speed, detective.
我只有几个问题
I just have a few questions.
凯特
Kate.
他们可以帮忙
They can help.
我明白调查这案子
I understand investigating this case
让你的处境非常艰难
puts you in a terribly difficult position.
但我必须跟你聊聊卡塞尔先生
But I need to talk to you about Mr. Castle.
除了他的家人
Outside of his family,
你是最了解他的人
You're the one who knew him best.
好吧  他很清白
Yeah, well, he didn't have any problems with...
不赌博  不缺钱  不吸毒
Gambling, money, drugs,
也没外遇  所以这些可以跳过了
Affairs, so we can skip all of that.
我知道他被绑的时候
I understand he was headed to the Hamptons
正开车前往汉普顿
When he was abducted.
对  我们的婚礼在那举办
Yeah. For our wedding.
还有谁知道他要开车去那里
Who knew he was making that drive?
婚礼的宾客
The wedding guests, um...
餐饮人员
Catering staff.
我需要他们的名字
I'll need their names.
我有名单
I've got a list.
但他们都是亲戚和朋友
But they're all friends and family.
以防万一
Still...
康纳探员  你觉得这会是绑架勒索吗
Agent Connors, do you think that this could be a ransom kidnapping?
如果是  我们会有所准备的
If it is, we'll be ready.
标准流程  我们会在卡塞尔先生家
It's standard protocol to set up a trap-and-trace
安装追踪装置
in Mr. Castle's loft...
以防绑匪打来
in the event kidnappers call.
我们还会监控家人的电话
We'll also monitor family cellphones.
听起来你好像并没指望会有绑匪打来
You sound like you don't expect those phones to ring.
康纳探员  你知道什么我不知道的事吗
Agent Connors, do you know something that I don't?
我只是一直在想
I just keep coming back to how much easier
如果在城里抓走卡塞尔会容易得多吧
it would've been to grab castle in the city.
可他们却偏要跑去长岛抓他
Instead, they took him on long island,
就在他要结婚的时候
just as he was about to get married...
跟你结婚
To you.
你觉得这事与我有关吗
Do you think that this has something to do with me?
你和卡塞尔先生合作破获过很多案子
You and Mr. Castle worked a lot of cases together.
会不会有谁想报复你
Could someone you went after have taken revenge?
有  有很多
Yeah. A lot of people.
好吧  我先去跟加里·达芬聊聊
Okay, well, I'll start by taking a run at Gary Duffin.
你去看看卷宗
You go through your case files,
列一个潜在嫌疑人的名单
come up with a list of potential suspects.
有发现及时通知我
Keep me apprised of what you find.
只要你也告诉我你的进展
As long as you do the same.
他会回来的
He'll come back.
当然会  亲爱的
Of course he will, darling.
你老爸很快就会回来的
Your father will be home before you know it.
谢谢
Thanks.
我们会找到他的
We'll find him.
康纳探员从达芬嘴里撬出什么了吗
So, was Agent Connors able to get anything out of Duffin?
一个字都没有  他回联调局总部去了
Not a word, so he went back to FBI HQ.
这些是你觉得可能会动卡塞尔的罪犯吗
Are those the perps you think might've made a move on castle?
对  首先就是布莱肯议员
Yeah. Starting with Senator Bracken.
你觉得是布莱肯指使的
Oh, you think Bracken's behind this?
我们毁了他的生活  还让他进了监狱
Well, we've ruined his life and had him sent to prison.
在卡塞尔前往婚礼的途中拿下他
Taking Castle down on his way to our wedding
太像他的作风了
would be just like him.
这么说的话  也可能是3XK
Or like 3XK, for that matter,
或是米基·巴博萨
Or Mickey Barbosa or any of the other
我们这几年抓获的好多人都有可能
dozens of people we've had put away over the past few years.
可能是他们中的任何人
I mean, it could be any of them.
也可能并不在这些人中
or none of them.
我们会查明白的  好吗
We're gonna figure this out, okay?
凯特  别沉浸在最糟的情况中
Kate, don't get lost in worst-case scenarios.
当初阿丽克西斯被绑的时候
When Alexis was taken,
最后发现跟卡塞尔的父亲有关
tied back to Castle's dad.
也许这事也跟他有关
Maybe he's mixed up in this,
如果这样的话  他一定会照顾他儿子的
And if he is, he's gonna look out for his son.
不过这事更像是跟黑帮有关
Except this is shaping up to be more mob-related.
为什么这么说
What makes you say that?
我查看了加里·达芬的通话记录
I ran Gary Duffin's cell records.
就在他粉碎那辆SUV之前
Right before he crushed that SUV,
刚刚和一个泽西黑帮成员通过话
he got a call from a Jersey Mobster.
那肯定就是那个
That must be the guy who ordered gary
下令粉碎那辆车的人  也解释了他为什么不敢招供
to squash that car, and why he's so scared to talk.
-这个黑手党是谁  -他叫文森特·卡达诺
- Who is this Mobster? - One Vincent Cardano.
文尼·卡达诺
Vinnie Cardano?
我见过他
I-I met him.
卡塞尔认识他
Castle knows him.
他们之间有矛盾吗
Was there ever a problem between them?
有  还真有
Yeah. There was.
绝对没有  相信我
No, there wasn't. Trust me.
我和卡塞尔关系很好的
Things are simpatico with me and Castle.
说实话  听说里克失踪了我很难过呢
Fact is, it pains my soul that Rick is missing.
我能做点什么
What can I do to help?
你和他生气大吵一架的当晚我也在场
I was there the night that you got angry with him and stormed out.
他基本上说我是个杀人犯哎
He near accused me of murder.
他质疑了我的正直
He impugned my integrity.
但是我们早就和好了
But we made our peace ages ago
还喝了瓶上好的瓦尔波利塞拉葡萄酒呢
over a nice bottle of valpolicella.
那你今天为什么要给加里·达芬打电话
Then why did you call Gary Duffin earlier today?
是让他去  粉碎某辆SUV吗
Was it to tell him to destroy a certain SUV?
这事和SUV有什么关系
What's an SUV got to do with this?
它和卡塞尔的绑架有关
It was involved in Castle's abduction.
这我真不知道
This I did not know.
但你确实让加里粉碎那辆车了
But you did have Gary crush that car.
这件事的界限比较模糊
We're entering into a gray area here.
你是个绑架案从犯
Uh, you're an accessory to kidnapping.
这没什么难界定的
There's nothing gray about that.
我说了  凯特
I'm telling you, Kate,
我没有绑架里克
I did not have Rick grabbed.
那就别再遮遮掩掩了
Then stop playing games
告诉我  你为什么要下令粉碎那辆车
and tell me -- why did you have the car crushed?
文尼
Vinnie,
你说你想要帮他的
you said that you wanted to help him.
现在就是帮他的机会
This is your chance.
好吧
Okay, listen.
又时候  会有客户需要让一辆车消失
On occasion, clients might need to make a vehicle disappear,
一万块钱
and for 10 grand,
这事就能解决
such a thing can be handled.
-这位客人叫什么  -都是不问名字的
- What was the name of the client? - No names came up.
他早上给我来电话  告诉我要求
He called me in the morning. He said the right things.
敲定交易
We struck a deal.
但我们没有见面  都是匿名完成的
But I never met the man. It was all anonymous.
那怎么给你付钱呢
Then how did you get paid?
定点放钱
We used a drop.
那辆SUV被压扁之后
A client left a bag full of cash in a dumpster
一个客人在下东区的一个垃圾箱
in the lower east side right after the SUV
留下了一个装钱
got turned into a panini.
之后
After?
如果你粉碎了车
What happens if you crush a car
但他们不付钱怎么办
and then you don't get your money?
这种事不会发生
That does not happen.
这个垃圾箱在哪
Where exactly is this dumpster?
根据卡达诺所说
Based on what Cardano said,
这就是交钱地点
this is the drop point.
我们在看什么
Now, what are we looking at here?
这不是街区监控
This is not street-cam footage.
这个地区没有街区监控
There's no coverage in the area,
但是一系列闯空门事件发生后
but after a rash of break-ins,
一栋大楼装上了隐蔽监控摄像头
one of the buildings installed hidden cameras,
我进了它的系统
and I was able to tap in.
这是交钱
This is in the time window
应该发生的时段
when the drop should've taken place.
如果我们找到了卡达诺的客人
If we get eyes on Cardano's client,
也就找到了抓走卡塞尔的人的线索
we can get a real lead on who took Castle.
这里  倒带
There. Go back.
就是他  那个客人  丢下了现金
That's him. That's the client, dropping off the cash.
我去安排排查  总该有人
I'll set up a canvass. Someone had
看见了他是从哪来到哪去的
to see where this guy came from or where he went.
是  我是埃斯波西托
Yeah, this is Esposito.
-给我接行动组  -等等  暂停
- Connect me with operations. - Wait. Freeze that.
放大
Zoom in.
不会吧
Can't be.
没错  那是卡塞尔
It is. That's Castle.
交钱的人是他
He's the one who dropped off the cash?
要我再放一遍吗
Do you want me to run it again?
我需要出去冷静一下
I need to get some air.
托瑞  再放一遍吧  谢谢
Yeah, Tory, one more time, please.
你觉得能还看出什么新花样吗
What are you gonna see that you didn't see before?
也许我们是忽略了哪一点
Maybe we missed something.
确实是忽略了一点
Yeah, we missed something.
卡塞尔也参与了此事  整个事件就是他策划的
Castle's in on this. He planned the whole thing.
也许这并不是他本人
Maybe it isn't really him.
想想看
Just think about it.
3XK的案子  让一个很相像的人
3Xk, he used a look-alike
想嫁祸他一桩谋杀罪
to try to frame him for murder --
-那人和卡塞尔长的一模一样  -不
- a guy with castle's face. - No.
不  凯文  这次不仅是长相
No, Kevin, it wasn't just his face.
那是他的衣服
It was his clothes.
他的动作  他的身体
It was his movements, his body.
那就是他本人  一个人
It was him, on his own
而且是在我们以为他被绑架几小时后
just hours after he was supposedly abducted.
贝克特  这完全说不通
Beckett, this doesn't make any sense.
卡塞尔不会那么做的  不会的
He wouldn't do that, not Castle.
调查一下卡塞尔  好吗
Look into Castle, okay?
看看他失踪前做过什么
Find out what he did, who he...
跟谁谈过
who he talked to just before he went missing,
然后  跟康纳探员汇报一下
and, brief Agent Connors.
你打算干什么
What are you gonna do now?
我要去跟他家人谈谈
I'm gonna talk to his family.
这些照片是在车祸之后
And these images were taken after the accident,
-起火之后拍的  -是的
- the car fire? - Yes.
这说明他还活着
So, he's alive!
-他没有被什么人绑架  -等一下
- He's not being held captive by God knows who. - Wait.
你是说老爸的车被一辆SUV撞到路边后
Are you saying dad was run off the road by an SUV
他花钱让人把那辆车报废掉
And after that, he paid to have it crushed?
-看上去是这样的  -太荒唐了
- It looks that way, yeah. - Well, that's ridiculous.
他为什么要这么做
Why on earth would he do such a thing?
他是不是遇到了我并不知情的什么事
Was he going through anything that I didn't know about?
什么事
Like what?
有什么压力  他自己一个人扛着
Pressure that he was under that he kept to himself.
当然没有
Of course not.
对吧  奶奶
Right, gram?
没有  没有  有的话我会发现的
No, no, no, no. I would've noticed.
那关于婚礼呢
And what about the wedding?
他是不是有什么疑虑
Did he have any misgivings?
疑虑
Misgivings?
凯萨琳
Katherine.
他绝对不可能有疑虑
That was the farthest thing from his mind.
他都等不及要娶你了
He couldn't wait to be married to you.
你不会觉得他是逃掉了吧
You don't think he'd just walk away, do you?
不
No.
那你是什么意思
Then what's going on here?
不知道
I don't know.
但肯定有别的原因
But there's got to be another explanation.
我觉得没有
I don't think there is.
那段视频清楚得显示了卡塞尔活得好好的
The video clearly shows Castle out in the world,
没有被胁迫
not under duress.
这改变了案子的情况
It changes the dynamics of the case.
不  这还是一起绑架案
No, this is still a kidnapping.
那段视频可能是假的
That video could be a fake.
只能说明卡塞尔扔掉了一包东西
All it shows is Castle throwing away a bag.
-可能是一个月之前拍的  -不是
- That could've been shot a month ago. - It wasn't.
我们的技术组分析了那段视频
Our tech team analyzed the footage.
是真实的
It's authentic.
你知不知道他在失踪前取了一大笔现金
Were you aware he withdrew a large sum just before he disappeared?
是的  是为了我们的蜜月
Yes. It was for our honeymoon.
文尼·卡达诺
Vinnie Cardano
把垃圾箱里的一万块钱上交了
turned over the $10,000 that was left in the dumpster.
就是卡塞尔取的那笔钱
It's the same money that Castle withdrew.
这不可能
That's not possible.
那是因为你沉浸在自己的想法里
That's because you're locked into your own version of events,
警探  我可以给你看纸币
But, detective, I can show you those bills,
钱的序号是吻合的
The matching serial numbers.
肯定有什么别的事
There's something else going on.
一定是
There has to be.
一切都清楚了
It all lines up,
卡塞尔认识卡达诺
right down to the fact that Castle knew Cardano,
知道他能让车辆消失
knew he could make cars vanish.
所以呢
So...  what?
他费了这么大劲
He went through this charade
就是为了让自己消失吗
just to stage his own disappearance?
为什么
Why?
人是很复杂的
People are complex.
可能他崩溃了  或者遇到了危机
Maybe he had a breakdown or a personal crisis.
也可能他有秘密的一面
And maybe there's a secret side to the man
别人都不知道
that nobody knows.
包括你
Including you.
听我说  康纳探员
Look, Agent Connors...
我知道现在有很多无法解答的问题
I know that there are a lot of unanswered questions here,
但你必须得继续找他
but you cannot stop looking for him.
我们会追查每一条线索
We'll follow every lead to the end.
但如果线索都断了
But once those leads dry up,
我们就只能缩小调查的规模了
we have to scale back our investigation.
我一定会找到卡塞尔
I will find Castle.
无论有没有联调局的帮助
With or without the FBI.
你是假设他想被人找到
You're assuming he wants to be found.
我是凯特·贝克特探长
My name is Detective Kate Beckett.
纽约警局凶案组的
I'm calling from the New York homicide division...
想问一下最近有没有...
Calling to see if there was any recent activity...
有没有一个叫理查德·卡塞尔的男士
To see if you had a gentleman named Richard Castle
在过去48小时内入住你们的酒店
check into your hotel over the last 48 hours.
身高大约一米八七
He's about 6'2".
查查当地航空公司  加油站
Take a look at local airlines, gas stations...
调出交通监控视频
and pull traffic cameras.
交通录像  汉普顿的交通摄像头
Traffic footage. Traffic cams in the Hamptons.
过去的48小时  所有你能找到的
Past 48 hours. Anything you can get me.
汉普顿的吗
For the Hamptons?
...卡塞尔的神秘失踪
Castle's mysterious disappearance.
联调局探员们已经离开了纽约警局12分局
FBI agents left the NYPD's 12th precinct.
马克  你能帮我接一下法国领事馆吗
Hey, Mark, can you put me in to the French Consulate?
我是从美国打来的
Calling from the United State.
我需要跟...  我是一名警探
I need to speak with the... Je suis un détective.
是关于一位理查德·卡塞尔先生
In regards to a Richard Castle.
汉普顿那边有什么新消息吗
Okay, anything coming out of the Hamptons?
过去两周内  我去看下我邮箱
For the past two weeks, yeah. Okay, I'll look for it in my e-mail.
不  我现在就要
No, I need it right away.
我们是美国海岸警卫队
This is the United States coast guard.
如果你遇险或需要帮助
Please respond if you are in distress
请予以回应
or need assistance.
海岸警卫队巡逻时在特拉华口岸80里外处
He was found adrift 80 miles off the coast of Delaware
发现他昏迷躺在一艘小艇上
by a coast guard cutter that was out there mapping the currents.
船长认出了卡塞尔  并把他送到了这里
Captain recognized who he was and had him airlifted here.
他在大西洋上干什么
What was he doing in the middle of the Atlantic ocean?
而且还是在一个有三个弹孔的小艇上
Yeah, especially in a dinghy with three bullet holes in it.
-他中枪了吗  -船长说他没有  但医生拒绝
-He was shot? - The captain said no, but the doctors here
向我们告知他的最新情况
won't give us any updates on his condition.
玛莎和阿丽克西斯在哪
Where are Martha and Alexis?
-坐巡逻车正赶过来呢  -知道了
- In a patrol car on their way in now. - Okay.
凯特
Kate?
我没事
I'm fine.
我只是没想到还能再见到他
I just never thought I'd see him again.
卡塞尔
Castle.
你好吗
Hey.
是我
It's me.
爸爸
Dad?!
理查德  亲爱的
Richard, darling.
他怎么了
What's wrong with him?
卡塞尔身上没什么明显伤痕
Mr. Castle hasn't sustained any serious injuries,
身体也在好转
and his vital signs continue to improve,
但他需要时间
But he is recovering
从暴晒和脱水中恢复过来
from the effects of exposure and dehydration.
可他为什么还不醒呢
Why hasn't he regained consciousness?
我们在做其它测试  希望能找出原因
We're running some additional tests to find out,
但目前为止
but at this point,
没什么要特别担心的
we don't think there's any cause for alarm.
如果允许的话
But we'd like to stay with him,
我们想陪在他身边
keep him company, if that's all right.
-没问题  -谢谢你
- Of course. - Thank you.
凯特
Kate!
他怎么样了
How is he?
情况稳定了  但依然昏迷不醒
He's stable, but he's still unconscious.
-我们还是不知道发生什么了吗  -是的
- So we still don't know what happened to him? - No.
有什么我能帮得上忙的
Well, if there's anything I can do...
我需要你帮忙看看他
Actually, yeah, I need you to take a look at him.
你知道的  看病不是我专长
You do know living patients aren't my thing, right?
不  蕾妮  我不是要你诊断他
No, Lanie, look, I don't want you to treat him.
我只是要你看看有何蹊跷之处
I want you to look at him as if it was a case.
有没有留下什么证据
See if you can find any evidence
证明他去过哪   经历过什么
of where he's been - and what he's been through.
-我尽量仔细查查  -好
- I'll see what I can do. - Okay. - All right.
我和贝克特一样
I'm with Beckett --
没想过还能见到卡塞尔
I never thought we'd see Castle again.
不过
Still...
他这段时间去哪了
Where's he been?
你看那些弹孔了
You saw those bullet holes.
也许是他试图从绑架者那逃出来时留下的
Maybe he used the boat to escape from whoever abducted him.
他伪造自己的绑架案  然后跑掉
The guy faked his own kidnapping and then ran off.
他怎么能这么对贝克特呢
Now, how could he do that to Beckett?
我们了解卡塞尔  并肩奋战了这么久
As long as we've known him, worked with him,
你就不能在证据不足的情况下  相信他吗
don't you think Castle deserves the benefit of the doubt?
兄弟们  没人知道卡塞尔身上发生了什么
You guys, none of us knows the truth about Castle.
至少到目前为止
Not yet.
埃斯波  你知道吗
And, Espo, you know what?
如果你是错的  那他就是受害者
If you're wrong, then he was a victim.
与其我们在这等着他苏醒
So instead of us just standing around
不如我们去查查
waiting for him to wake up, why don't we start
那艘小艇是谁的
by figuring out who owns that dinghy?
已经在查了
Already on it.
那艘艇以前注册在
The boat had expired tags
佐治亚州萨凡纳市的柯蒂斯·霍尔特名下
registered to a Curtis Holt of Savannah, Georgia.
我们给他打了电话
We called holt.
他说一年前
He said that he sold it
在车库甩卖时卖掉了
over a year ago at a garage sale.
他想不起来卖给谁了
He can't recall who he sold it to.
查下他说的是否属实  同时找到当前所有者
Okay. Check his story. Find the current owner.
找到船主  我们就能知道
We find the owner, we'll figure out
卡塞尔去了哪
where Castle was coming from.
同时  我会去找船长谈谈
In the meantime, I'll talk to the ship's captain
看他能否提供其他线索
and see - if he can tell us anything else.
根据卡塞尔先生的状况  我猜测他已经
Based on Mr. Castle's condition, I'm guessing he'd been
在那小艇上躺了四五天
in that vessel four or five days.
那小艇会不会是某艘大船上的
Okay, could the dinghy have come from a larger boat?
不像
Not likely.
你看  艇上有保护油漆的碰垫
See, it has fenders, or pads, to protect the paint,
而且依碰垫的位置
and the position of the fenders
它应该是系在某个码头的
points to it being moored at a dock.
有办法查到是哪个码头吗
Is there any way to know where that dock is?
我只能告诉你我的猜测
I could give you my best guess.
小艇有六马力发动机
The dinghy had a six-horse motor,
如果油箱满油  能行驶两小时
two hours worth of fuel if the tanks were full.
待燃油耗尽  在海上飘个
After it ran dry, it drifted for...
四五天
four or five days.
结合风向风速和当时的水流矢量
So based on wind and current vectors,
它应该是从罗德岛和南缅因之间
it probably launched somewhere between Rhode island
的某个码头驶出的
and Southern Maine.
找到线索了
Looks like we caught a break.
那艘天蓝色的小艇
Turns out that sky-blue dinghy
出厂时是标准的白色
was a standard white when it came out of the factory.
这信息有什么用吗
And how does that help us?
前任船主重新改装过
Well, the previous owner pimped it out.
他加装了定制鱼竿架
He added custom fishing-rod holders
并把船漆成了天蓝色
and painted it sky-blue.
让这艘船几乎成了同类中独一无二的了
Making it a relative rarity in the world of dinghies.
根据船长告诉你的信息
So, going off what the captain told you,
我们发出了通告
we put out a bolo on all sky-blue dinghies
让从罗德岛到缅因州沿岸各执法部门留意
to all law enforcement along the coast
所有的天蓝色小艇
from Rhode island to Maine.
我们找到了
We got a hit.
马萨诸塞州格洛斯特的公园管理员
Park ranger in Gloucester, Massachusetts,
想起曾在一私人码头见过一艘
recalls seeing it at a private dock.
这是网上的卫星照片  摄于一个月前
This is a satellite photo off the web taken a month ago.
这就是公园管理员提到的私人码头
This is the private dock the ranger was talking about.
还有那艘天蓝色小艇
And there's the sky-blue dinghy.
连同定制的鱼竿架
Complete with custom fishing-rod holders.
和发现卡塞尔的那艘完全一样
Just like the one Castle was found in.
好  那么
Okay, so...
这看起来是个移动式住房
This looks like a mobile home.
这个码头是它的吗
Does the dock belong to it?
它们都是属于一个叫做
It's all part of the same property
亨利·詹金斯的财产
owned by one Henry Jenkins.
不论卡塞尔发生了什么
Whatever's going on with Castle,
这里就是源头
this is where he came from.
这家伙也肯定牵扯其中
And this guy must be involved.
谢谢替我们把控局面  西姆斯警佐
Thanks for holding down the fort, Sergeant Simms.
我只不过在这监视这移动式住房而已
All I did was hang around and watch a mobile home.
到底发生了什么
What's this all about?
我们要找户主  亨利·詹金斯  你认识吗
It's about the owner, Henry Jenkins. Do you know him?
不  我们不常来这附近
No. We don't get over here too much.
不论他是谁  他现在不在家
Whoever he is, he's not home.
我没看到有人走动
I didn't notice any signs of life.
接下来就交给我们吧
Okay, well, we'll take it over from here.
如果需要帮忙就用无线电呼叫我
I'm a radio call away if you need me.
多谢
Thank you.
看来亨利·詹金斯把他网上的踪迹都抹去了
Looks like Henry Jenkins scrubbed himself off the web.
托瑞能查到的我们都已经知道了
All Tory can find out is what we already know.
他在波士顿开了一家私人安保公司
He runs a private security firm in Boston.
我们还是不知道是什么样的安保公司
And we still don't know what kind of security.
是商场保安还是军事承包商呢
Are we talking mall cops or military contractor?
不论哪个  他都可以接触到枪械
Either way, that would give him access to firearms,
这也说明了船上为什么有弹孔
which could explain the bullet holes in the boat.
不过他和卡塞尔之间的联系又是什么呢
But what's the link between him and Castle?
为什么他会和这样一个人扯上关系
Why would he be mixed up with this guy?
是蕾妮  可能有什么消息
It's Lanie. She may have something.
就位
Stand by.
凯特  我说服卡塞尔的医生
Kate, I talked Castle's doctor
让我检查了一下
into letting me look him over,
我发现了一些  奇怪的东西
and I came across a few... strange things.
怎么奇怪
Strange how?
卡塞尔的衣服上没有任何线索
No trace evidence on Castle's clothes.
不过我找到一把缝到他裤子衬里的钥匙
But I did find a key sewn into the lining of his pants.
什么样的钥匙
What kind of a key?
我说不上来
I'm not sure,
不过上面有个"38"的印记
but it has "38" Stamped on it.
-能让你想到什么吗  -想不到
- That mean anything to you? - No.
好吧
Okay.
还有就是他的血液检查结果
Then there's his blood work.
我发现他有登革热的抗体
I found antibodies to dengue fever.
也就是说卡塞尔在过去两月里
That means Castle was exposed to the virus
曾感染过这病毒
within the last two months.
等等  登革热不是热带的吗
Wait. Isn't dengue fever tropical?
是啊
Yeah!
它主要分布在拉丁美洲
It's mostly found in Latin America,
非洲和亚洲
Africa, and Asia.
这一点也说不通啊
That doesn't make any sense.
我发现的枪伤也说不通
Neither does the bullet wound I found.
卡塞尔的肋下被子弹擦伤
Castle was grazed across the ribs.
这个还是可以说通的
Okay, that makes a little bit more sense.
艇上有弹孔
There were bullet holes on the boat.
可这伤口已基本愈合了
But this wound was mainly healed.
他是几周之前受伤的
He was shot a few weeks ago.
几周之前
A few weeks ago?
你确定吗
Are you sure?
或许更久
Maybe even longer.
凯特  卡塞尔到底遇上什么麻烦了
Kate, what the hell was Castle mixed up in?
我看见窗帘动了  里面有人
I just saw the curtain move. Someone's in there.
一会儿打给你
I'll call you back.
行动
Let's go.
你看到是什么人了吗
Did you get eyes on anyone?
没有
Negative.
趴在地上
On the ground!
马上趴在地上
Get down on the ground!
把你的手放在我能看见的地方  马上
Put your hands where I can see 'em now, now, now!
袋子里是什么
What's in the bags?
垃圾  垃圾
Trash! Trash!
我就是出来倒垃圾的
I was taking out the trash!
跟我说说理查德·卡塞尔
Talk to me about Richard Castle.
我跟你说了  我不认识这个人
I'm telling you, I don't know the guy.
我都根本没听说这个人
I mean, I've never even heard of him.
没有其他人来过的迹象
There's no sign that anyone else has been here.
因为就我一个会来这
'Cause no one comes here but me.
这里是我度周末的地方
This is my weekend place.
这是你的船  是吗
This is your boat, correct?
好像是
It would appear to be.
如果你不认识卡塞尔先生
If you don't know Mr. Castle,
那怎么会在海中央
then how did he end up in this boat
发现在他这条船上
in the middle of the ocean?
我不知道
I have no idea,
但我前几天来的时候
but I did notice that it was missing
确实注意到船不见了
when I came up here a few days ago.
你的船不见了  但是你却没有上报
So your boat was missing, but you didn't report that?
我从来不用那破玩意儿
I never use the damn thing.
我是说  我甚至不知道为什么买它
I mean, I don't -- I don't even know why I bought it.
我以为是船被解缆了  或者被偷了
I just figured it came unmoored or -- or got stolen.
谁会偷小艇
Who would steal a dinghy?
有个男的在沙滩旁转悠
Well, there was a man who hanging around down by the beach.
一个男的
A man?
形容一下他
Describe him.
快40了  个挺高
Um, late 30s, I would guess, uh, tall,
棕色头发  人高马大的
brown hair, big build.
对  就是他
Yeah. Yeah, th-that's definitely him.
他去过沙滩  他在那做什么
He was on the beach? What was he doing?
露营
Camping.
Camping?
-这不可能  -在一个帐篷里
-That can't be right. -In a tent.
他看起来忙着干自己的事
He was seemed to be minding his own business,
况且是在国有土地  所以我就没管他
and it was on state land, so I just left him alone.
莱恩  你来完成詹金斯先生的笔录
Ryan, can you finish taking Mr. Jenkins' statement?
那男的住在哪
Where exactly was this man?
这里就是栓那艘小艇的船坞
That's the dock - where the dinghy was tied up.
这是卡塞尔的鞋子
These are castle's shoes.
这是他的手表
This is his watch.
报纸
Newspapers.
两个月前的报纸了
Dating back two months.
衣服  物资  他在这设备齐全了
Clothes, supplies -- he has everything here.
他完全可以走到那辆拖车
He could've walked up to that trailer
打个电话
and made a phone call.
但他没有
But never did.
怎么了
What?
卡塞尔的结婚礼服
Castle's wedding tux?
卡塞尔醒了
Castle's awake.
真是个好消息
It's wonderful news --
医生刚刚告诉我
The doctor just told me
理查德将完全康复
Richard will make a full recovery.
我真是松了一口气
Oh, oh! I am so relieved!
我当时在场
Oh. And I was right there
理查德醒来的时候
when richard started to wake up.
他做的第一件事
First thing he did
就是找你
was ask for you.
他说了他到哪儿去了吗
Did he say where he had been?
我们不知道他经历了什么
You know, we don't know what he's been through,
或许这问题可以迟些再问
so perhaps that question can wait.
告诉你件事
Just so you know,
医生说接吻可以加速身体康复
the doctor said that kissing will speed my recovery.
接吻待会再说  卡塞尔
Kissing can wait, Castle.
好的  抱歉
Right. Sorry.
我想我让我们的婚礼计划打了结
I guess I put a little kink in our wedding plans.
你这是在开玩笑吗
Yeah, is that supposed to be a joke?
什么意思
What do you mean?
我的意思是告诉我发生了什么
I mean tell me what happened.
我在去参加婚礼的路上
Was on my way to the wedding,
有辆黑色的越野车
and this black SUV --
不  不是  这件事之后
No, no. After that.
车祸后的事吗
After the accident?
是的  车祸后的事
Yes, after the accident.
我就在这了
I was here.
不是  在这之前  卡塞尔
No, before here, Castle.
你在海上的一艘船里被找到
You were found in a boat at sea --
一艘看似是你偷来的船
A boat - that you apparently stole?
你到底在说什么
What are you talking about?
一艘  不  我出车祸了
A bo-- no, I was in a crash
和一辆黑色越野车相撞  之后就在这醒了
with a black SUV, - a-and then I woke up here.
不  告诉我在这其间发生了什么
No, tell me what happened in between.
什么也没有
Nothing.
我是说  我  我不知道
I mean, I-I don't -- I don't know.
我一直昏迷不醒
I was -- I was unconscious.
就是说黑色SUV和在医院醒过来
So the black SUV and waking up here,
你只记得这些了
that's all you remember?
是的  没错  干嘛这么问
Right. Yes. Why?
你已经失踪两个月了
You've been missing for two months.
你认为他这是怎么回事
What do you think is going on with him?
没有迹象显示卡塞尔先生有精神问题
Well, Mr. Castle shows no sign of a psychosis
或者现实感丧失
or break with reality,
也没有表现出认知障碍的迹象
nor does he exhibit cognitive deficits
除了他没办法回忆过去两个月发生的事情
other than his inability to recall the last two months.
也就是说可能是他遭遇过创伤
So is it possible that he underwent trauma,
封闭了这些记忆
and he's blocking it out?
有可能
He may have,
虽然我没看到任何这方面的证据
although I didn't see any evidence of that.
也许他会恢复记忆
Maybe his memory will come back
只要给他时间去重新适应
once he's had some time to readjust.
很有可能
It very well might.
那他需要的可能就是回归正常生活
Then what he needs, maybe, is to get back to his life,
他的日常工作  以及爱他的人
his routine, the people who love him.
我们能接他回家吗
Can't we just take him home?
你们得问他的医生
You'll have to speak with his doctors.
当然了  太感谢了
Of course, of course. Oh, thank you so much.
斯旺医生
Dr. Swann...
你觉得真正的原因是什么
What do you think - is really behind all of this?
我的工作并不是严谨科学  虽然我希望是
What I do is not an exact science. I wish it were.
失忆可能是情绪创伤导致的
This could still be the result of emotional trauma.
还有药物原因
There are also drugs
药物相互作用可以导致失忆
and drug interactions - that can trigger memory loss,
但是
but...
但是什么
But what?
我不能排除这种可能性
...I can't exclude the possibility
卡塞尔先生只是出于某种原因
that mr. Castle simply walked away from his life,
逃离生活
for whatever reason,
面对这一事实  对他来说太可耻
and facing that fact - is just too humiliating for him.
你觉得他可能假装失忆
So you think that he could be pretending not to remember?
我说过了  有可能
As I said, it's a possibility.
说我欠你一个道歉似乎完全不够
To say I owe you an apology seems an understatement.
我不要道歉  卡塞尔  我要弄清楚
I don't want an apology, Castle. I just want to understand.
你了解我的  凯特
Well, you know me, Kate.
我不会一走了之
I wouldn't just leave.
有证据
There's evidence.
我们找到了你待的地方
We found the place where you were staying.
哪里
Where?
知道又有什么区别
What difference does it make?
我想去那里  也许能帮我恢复记忆
Because I want to go there. Maybe it'll help me remember.
无论发生了什么  我需要答案
Whatever happens, I need answers.
你也一样
And so do you.
我不明白
I don't get it.
卡塞尔怎么会离开  去露营
How could Castle - just leave and go...Camping?
你不是要选择相信他吗
What happened to giving him the benefit of the doubt?
贝克特叫我让鉴证组
Beckett asked me to have CSU take a look
检查帐篷内的东西
at the contents of the tent.
哈维  你是对的
Javi, you were right.
报纸上全是卡塞尔的指纹
Castle's fingerprints - were all over the newspaper,
帐篷里全是他的毛发  DNA
All his stuff -- hair, DNA.
我没办法解释
I can't explain that away.
这次真没办法
Not this time.
有点让我想起  汉普顿或是缅因州
Kind of reminds me - of the Hamptons or Maine,
但我肯定我没来过这里
but I'm pretty sure I've never been here.
就是这里
Okay, this is it.
你的帐篷就在这里
This is where your tent was.
这里一切看起来都不熟悉
No, none of this looks familiar.
卡塞尔  告诉我真相
Castle, just tell me the truth.
这是你欠我的
You owe me that much.
我是在告诉你真相  我没来过这里
I am telling you the truth. I was not here.
你的衣服在这里
Well, your clothes were here.
你的表  你的礼服
Your watch was here, your tuxedo...
你娶我时要穿的那套
The one that you were gonna wear when you married me.
肯定是布的局  和...
It must've been planted here, you know, along with --
没什么布局  卡塞尔  你曾经在这里
Nothing was planted, Castle. It was you.
-有你的DNA和指纹  -化验室肯定搞错了
- It was your DNA, your prints. - Must've been a mistake at the lab.
-有许多案件...  -我相信你
- There have been numerous cases -- - I believed in you. I...
我说服自己  证据并不重要
I convinced myself - that the evidence didn't matter,
这一切太明显
that everything that seemed so obvious
不可能是真的
couldn't possibly be true.
我到处搜寻你
I was searching for you.
我甚至不知道你是生还是死
I didn't even know if you were alive or if you were dead,
你却在这里  待在你想待的地方
And you were right here, right where you wanted to be.
我向你发誓
I promise you...
我没有在这里搭帐篷
I did not pitch a tent here.
我不可能
I could not have.
我亲眼见到的  卡塞尔
I saw it for myself, Castle.
我永远不可能在这个地方搭帐篷
I would never camp in this spot,
在我为《热带斯道姆》做调研后绝对不会
Not after the research I did on "Tropical Storm."
我根本没办法和你沟通了
I can't even do this with you.
等等  听我说
Hey, wait. Listen.
你从来没写过名为《热带斯道姆》的书  卡塞尔
You never wrote a book called "Tropical storm," Castle.
凯特  等等
Kate, wait.
听我说
Listen.
我开始写了  后来放弃了
I started the book. I threw it out.
本来写的是超级恶人控制天气
It was, uh -- super-villain controls the weather.
很可怕
It was terrible, but it --
但我对灾难性暴风雨的研究
The research I did on catastrophic storms --
让我挥之不去  让我从此
It stuck with me, leaving me with
对海啸有了不合理但是无法抵抗的恐惧
an irrational but overpowering fear of tsunamis.
你在汉普顿买了海边别墅
You bought a beach house in the Hamptons.
靠内陆  不是海边
Yeah, on the inland side, not on the ocean side.
凯特
Kate...
我不会在这里露营的  我会选高一点的地方
I would never camp here. I would go for higher ground.
卡塞尔
Castle...
有证人
There was a witness.
什么证人
What witness?
有什么事
Can I help you?
纽约警局
Yeah. NYPD.
我来找亨利·詹金斯
I'm here to see Henry Jenkins?
我是亨利·詹金斯
I'm Henry Jenkins.
不好意思  我昨天来过了
I'm sorry. I was here yesterday,
我见到的是另一个亨利·詹金斯
and I met a different Henry Jenkins.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我是亨利·詹金斯
I'm Henry Jenkins,
而且我好几个月没来过这了
and I haven't been here in months.
我们查了指纹和护照
We ran prints and passport.
他绝对是货真价实的亨利·詹金斯
He is definitely the real Henry Jenkins.
也就是说第一个人是假詹金斯
Which means the first guy was a fake Jenkins --
还是个骗子
also, a liar.
但他跟车管所备案的照片匹配啊
But he matched the DMV photo.
那是因为车管所的照片被掉包了
That's because his photo got switched.
我们打电话给车管所时  他们发现自己的系统
When we called the DMV, they realized their system
在两天前被黑了
had been hacked two days ago,
正是新闻报道说我被找到的时候
right after the news broke that I'd been found.
那帐篷里你的那些东西呢
What about all your stuff in the tent?
看来那些东西
Well, it looks like
都是被设计好的  为了留下假线索
it was all set up in order to create a false trail.
那你为什么失忆呢
So why don't you remember anything?
这些人试图让整件事看起来
Uh, these people have managed to make it look
像是我筹划绑架了自己
as though I staged my own abduction.
他们黑了车管所系统
They hacked the DMV.
弄了个假詹金斯出来
They provided a false Jenkins
把你们引向预先准备好的证据
who pointed you to doctored evidence
让你们以为我去露营了
that I'd gone camping.
不管这些是什么人  他们有无限的资源
Whoever they are, they have unlimited resources,
也许他们甚至有
maybe the kind of resources that would allow them
可以改变别人记忆的资源
to alter someone's memory.
那笔钱又怎么解释呢
What about the money?
什么钱
What money?
监控录像拍到你在被绑架后
We have you on video dropping off
还曾把一万美金丢在了指定的垃圾桶里
$10,000 in a dumpster after you were taken.
我现在还无法解释那件事
Yeah, I can't explain the money yet.
但我早晚会的
But I will.
假詹金斯参与其中
And fake Jenkins was part of the setup.
所以不管他是谁
So whoever he is,
他都跟这件事脱不了干系
he's somehow in the middle of this.
好了  亲爱的
Here you go, darling.
谢谢  妈妈  请允许我引用
Thank you, mother, and let me just say,
桃乐茜[《绿野仙踪》女主]的不朽名言
in the immortal words of Dorothy,
"无处如家"
"There's no place like home."
我不明白的是
Here's what I don't get.
为什么会有人如此对你呢  爸
Why would someone do this to you, dad?
你这两个月到底跑哪去了
Where did you actually go for two months?
那些答案都藏在
Well, those answers lie
其背后巨大狡猾的阴谋中
within the vast and insidious conspiracy behind all this,
我下定决心要解开这张
a tangled web that I fully intend to...
错综复杂的迷网
untangle.
别再说这件事了
Enough of that.
我想敬个酒
I'd like to propose a toast.
敬平安回家
To safe returns.
还要敬再不分离
And no more departures.
还要敬我伟大的母亲
And to my amazing mother...
聪慧的女儿
my wonderful daughter...
和我一生的挚爱
and the love of my life.
敬回家
And to coming home.
我们会搞清楚到底发生了什么
We'll find out what happened.
我知道
I know.
我只是在想
I was just thinking...
我觉得好像昨天还戴过这块表
I feel like I just wore this yesterday,
昨晚还和你一起睡在这张床上
that we slept in this bed last night.
对你来说  这肯定是恍如隔世了
For you, it must seem like a lifetime ago.
是  没错
Yeah, it does.
你是怎么做到不放弃希望的呢
How did you not lose hope?
我失去过希望  你知道吗
I did lose hope, you know?
但是我
But I...
我还是会把它找回来
I would get it back.
我为了保持希望而想出了很多仪式
Developed rituals in order to hang on to it.
什么仪式
Like what?
很傻的  不说也罢
It's...stupid. It really doesn't matter.
不  我想听
No, I'd like to know.
我会一直盯着谋杀板上你的照片看
I would stare at your photo on the murder board.
我开始觉得
And I started thinking
只要我每天看的时间够长
that if I would look at it long enough every day,
你就能活着
that that would keep you alive.
看来管用了
I guess it worked.
还有你的椅子
And then I had this thing about your chair.
我在分局的椅子吗
My chair at the precinct?
我不让任何人碰它
I wouldn't let anyone touch it.
有天晚上清洁工来打扫
And then a night janitor came by.
他想挪开椅子  我就疯了  我
He tried to move the chair, and I freaked out, and I...
我差点开枪毙了他
almost shot him.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry...
让你受了这么多罪
for everything I put you through.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault, you know.
你也受了很多罪  所以
You went through stuff, too, so...
这不一样
Well, it's not the same.
我不记得了
I can't remember.
虽然我确定地知道我肯定很想你
Though I do know I missed you terribly,
因为我不可能不想你
because there's no way I wouldn't.
我们不能
We can't just, um...
接着之前的日子过  就好像
pick up where we left off, can we,
这一切都没发生过  对吧
as if nothing happened?
不行
No.
会过去的
We'll get there.
我们会找到回家的路
We'll find our way home.